# **Matthew Gouvin**

A software engineer who uses modern technologies to design, build and test software and web applications; interested in machine learning and data visualization. Searching for an internship in software engineering to gain hands-on experience with emerging technologies and to develop mentorships with experienced engineers.

### Education

#### THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

Washington, D.C.

B.S. Computer Science. GPA 3.98.

May 2024

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Database Systems, Data Structures & Algorithms.

Awards: Dean's List 2020-2022

#### CHARIHO HIGH SCHOOL

Wood River Junction, RI

Graduated as valedictorian with high honors.

June 2020

National Honor Society. Editor-in-Chief of school newspaper. President of the Chariho High School Chorus.

# **Experience**

#### SURVICE ENGINEERING COMPANY

Belcamp, MD

# **Software Development Intern**

May 2022 - Present

- Devised, implemented, and tested advanced features for four web applications with thousands of active users.
- Leveraged MySQL, Express, NodeJs, and Angular to respectively make database schema changes, create RESTful API endpoints, engineer useful API services, and build user-friendly components.
- Optimized application performance by reducing API call time by over 75% in some instances.
- Collaborated with team members, reviewed code daily, and worked in an agile development environment.

### USABLE SECURITY AND PRIVACY LAB

Washington, D.C.

### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

March 2022 – May 2022

- Examined security differences between applications on the Google Play Store and applications on five third-party application stores.
- Formulated a relational database schema using MySQL to store application data collected from web-scraping tools and public APIs.
- Participated in weekly reading groups, discussion groups and scrum meetings.

# THE WESTERLY SUN

Westerly, RI

## **Contributing Writer**

July 2019 – June 2021

- Authored over 25 stories for communities in southwestern Rhode Island.
- Provided extensive reporting for stories related to education, municipal government, and local elections.
- Conducted research by interviewing community members, collecting data, and investigating points of controversy.

# **Technical Projects**

#### UNIVERSITY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

**Co-Creator** 

Spring 2022

- Created a responsive web application that manages college applications, class registration, and academic advising.
- Designed the relational database schema, implemented it with Amazon Web Services, and utilized the database in the management of personnel and course information.

### **Technical Skills**

Programming: Java, C, Python, JavaScript (Node.js), Typescript (Angular), SQL (MySQL, SQLite), HTML, CSS, R.

**Operating Systems:** Windows, MAC OS, Linux. **Web Design:** Designed <a href="https://www.mattgouvin.me">www.mattgouvin.me</a>.